Congratulations on
finishing this course.
Making it this far in
the program is quite
the accomplishment.
You should be excited
about your progress.
You're this much
closer to building
the know-how you need to
be a project manager.
In this last set of videos,
I went over how to
formally close a project
and explained why closing
a project is important.
I defined what it means for
a project to be complete,
detailed the steps in
the closing phase,
and I demonstrated how to create
documentation for
closing a project.
We learned that project closing,
when applied appropriately, is
a combination of assurance
that the work has been completed,
confirmation that all agreed upon
project management processes
have been executed,
and formal recognition that
the project
requirements have been
met and everyone agrees that
the project is, in fact, done.
We discussed different aspects
of the closing process,
including conducting
retrospectives for your team,
why impact reporting matters,
and the purpose of a
project closeout report.
That was the end.
Throughout the entire course,
you learned how to run a project.
This is no small feat.
We discussed that tracking
a project helps to
build and maintain
confidence within your team that
the project will be
delivered on time,
on budget, and in-scope.
We learned about different
external factors that impact
a project like dependencies,
risk, and changes.
We discussed how to communicate
those factors to
your team members.
We covered data,
how to gather it,
how to use it to inform
decision-making processes,
and how to discern and explain
project data using effective
presentation techniques.
We discussed how
projects, programs,
and portfolios relate to each
other and their key differences.
We also learned about the
elements of teamwork and how
a successful project
manager leads a team to
success with positive influence
and ethical considerations.
At this point, you should have
a good understanding of how to
organize and facilitate meetings
to ensure project success
and how to communicate effective
project status updates
to stakeholders.
The next course is all about
Agile project management.
Thanks for allowing me to
share my knowledge with you.